Tanner Hearne

- hello@tannerhearne.com
- http://www.tannerhearne.com

SUMMARY

User Experience Expert with a focus on executing solid mobile and desktop strategy as it relates to user engagement and online marketing. Emphasis on communicating well across digital media and how to utilize effective user experience through coordination of interdisciplinary teams.

Core Skills: User Experience, Responsive Web Design, Web Application Development, User Interface Design, Mobile Websites, Mobile Web Applications, Native Mobile Applications, Tablet Websites, Tablet Web Applications, Online Branding, Internet Marketing, iOS Design Tools: HTML5, CSS3, Sass, LESS, Twitter Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Grunt, Codekit, Git, PHP, Laravel PHP Framework, MySQL, WordPress, Google Analytics, Google Webmaster Tools, Adobe Suite, Browserstack, Beanstalk, Basecamp, Project Management Tools Experience: - 6+ years of digital design experience - 4+ years of development experience - Solid understanding of digital interfaces using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript and how it relates to backend applications running in PHP - Mastery of development of web applications in PHP - Specific concentration on mobile interfaces and user experience and how it relates to site or application usability - Strong evangelist for cross-screen compatibility and easy-to-use interfaces - Proponent of analytics based data as it relates to conversions and user experience

SKILLS

- HTML 5
- Web Design
- JavaScript
- Web Development
- Photoshop
- Interactive Marketing
- Business Development
- Technology Management
- Technical Leadership
- Laravel
- Business Strategy

- Mobile Applications
- PHP
- CSS
- CSS3
- Illustrator
- iOS Design
- Web Applications
- Strategic Leadership
- Adobe Creative SuiteInnovation
- Cross-functional Team Leadership

EXPERIENCE

The Music Bed

Director of Technology

02 / 2014 - Present

Responsible for leadership of technology and development resources and development.

- Defines direction of new technology.
- Requirement gathering and development planning.
- Leads The Music Bed's team of developers.
- Facilitates communication funnel between The Music Bed and external development and technology teams.
- Interacts with third parties while setting monthly forecasts.
- Manages the priority of on-going projects and prepares revised project delivery plans.

The Music Bed

Responsible for all management of technology and development resources and product and technology development.

- Assists in direction of new technology.
- · Requirement gathering and development planning.
- Weekly status updates and discussions on ongoing projects.
- Manages communication funnel between The Music Bed and any external development and technology teams.
- Interacts with third parties while sending monthly forecasts of work.
- Manages the priority list of on-going projects and prepares revised project delivery plans.

Steadfast Creative

03 / 2012 - 05 / 2013

Principal/Development Director

Responsible for all product development for client and proprietary projects. Managed a team of developers and designers who developed online marketing and tools for major companies and organizations.

- Introduced design methodology shift to heavily optimize for both mobile and retina-ready
 web interfaces and user experience using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, and Sass.
- More than tripled development profit growth potential through improving product quality and optimizing product development process.
- Increased product performance and security while reducing risk through implementing advanced server-side services.
- Enacted ongoing revenue model and enduring client relationship by creating monitoring and hosting products.

Exclusr 12 / 2011 - 09 / 2012

Lead User Experience and Product Designer

Exclusr is a nightlife application built to offer increased sales potential for nightlife venues and increased user engagement through the use of digital deal system. Exclusr allows venues to easily communicate with their patrons via highly localized interactions.

- Cast design and user experience vision for native iOS user mobile application and desktop venue web application built on Java.
- Created compelling interface and user experience that received very high praise.
- Designed and built interactive iPad presentations used by salespeople to demo application to client venues.
- Designed and developed application marketing site using techniques to show mobile functionality realistically to site visitors.

BigBadCollab

06 / 2011 - 10 / 2011

User Experience Intern

Brought into process at every stage of very large web application projects. Designed and maintained websites built on custom CMS created in PHP. Collaborated with team members and outside partner companies.

Bethesda Community Church

01 / 2008 - 06 / 2011

Digital Media Coordinator

Operated a thorough and solid operation that supplied media for live events. Visual, Audio and Lighting all played a part and were all managed. Designed presentations, print materials and digital ads.

Innovative Shopping, LLC.

03 / 2010 - 08 / 2010

User Experience Designer

Designed all user interface and focused user experience. Increased website usability working directly with SEO strategist. Designed, developed, and launched website for "10,000 Bids" contest in under 24 hours.

EDUCATION

The University of Texas at Arlington

2010 - 2012

Bachelor of Arts (BA), Communication Technology

Tarrant County College

2008 - 2010

Associate of Arts (A.A.)

Cornerstone Honors Program

INTERESTS

new technology, internet, web, mobile, apps, design, development, innovation, creative thinking, ideas, challenging the norm, leadership

LANGUAGES

English

• Spanish